Roland Nyamoga

roland.n1844@gmail.com | 1-616-216-3589

SUMMARY

I am a Principal Product and Program Manager, former Network and Solutions Architect with expertise across **Azure**, **AWS**, **and hybrid networking**. I have been accountable for enterprise-scale connectivity strategy across continents. Proven track record leading **crossfunctional programs** spanning engineering, product, and operations across global time zones.

SELECTED EXPERIENCE AND INITIATIVES

Selected projects relevant to the role.

Shanghai Co-Lo Hybrid connectivity: Led architecture and deployment of P&G's Shanghai colocation facility with 21Vianet. My responsibilities included:

- Cloud -> DC architecture and connectivity: circuit ordering, BGP configuration and design, ExpressRoute/Direct Connect configuration and implementation
- Project management and communication
- Change management: cutover schedule, plan and execution.

Global DNS Migration: Led the global DNS appliance upgrade for 100s of sites from DiamondIP to Infoblox. This included anycast VIP DNS and networking layer configuration. We had a successful cutover.

Direct Connect + ExpressRoute provisioning automation: I automated direct connect and ExpressRoute hybrid network provisioning given it was a lot of repetitive tasks. This included:

- IP address allocation (Infoblox API)
- BGP configuration

My automation generated a compliant configuration, ready to be deployed across multiple networking devices.

Self-Service Network Insights Platform: Designed internal developer-facing APIs to expose near real-time network metadata. Reduced investigation time-to-triage by $\sim 90\%$ and enabled future graph-based automation.

Search and Ranking Foundations: Enabled customer image and text AI search by designing an ETL pipeline ingesting multisource data into DynamoDB and OpenSearch to power customer service discovery (text and image vectors), data tagging and quality scoring for better, more relevant results.

Go-to-Market and comms: Authored product briefs, release notes, executive comms on products and programs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Cloud Solutions Architect -> Sr/Principal Program Manager - Azure, Microsoft | 2020 - Present

- Advised Fortune 500 clients on **cloud landing zones**, **governance**, **and compliance** across Azure and AWS.
- Guided customers on complex cloud architecture strategy for RBAC, compute, networking
- **Drove multi-cloud and multi-org programs** including ImpactRP and AI-driven diagnostics platforms, aligning engineering and product teams worldwide.

Senior Manager / Hybrid Cloud Network Architect - Procter & Gamble | Jun 2018 - Apr 2020

- **Deployed modern spine-leaf datacenter architectures**, improving resiliency and east-west performance at scale.
- Accountable for **global hybrid connectivity architecture**, ensuring high availability and scalability across AWS, Azure, and Office 365 across the globe.
- **Designed and deployed multiple colocation facilities** in partnership with **Equinix** and **21Vianet (China)** to deliver redundant, resilient, and low-latency cloud connectivity globally.
- Procured, configured and operated **peering circuits, cross-connects** to support a cloud-first, globally distributed enterprise.
- Championed infra-as-code adoption to modernize traditional networking operations, supporting faster, repeatable, and rollback-capable deployments.

Cloud Network Engineer - Amway Global | Nov 2017 - Jun 2018

- Automated AWS VPC, Direct Connect, and load balancer provisioning with CloudFormation, reducing provisioning from days to minutes.
- Built a secure, automated private cloud DMZ for public-facing workloads.
- Led IX Peering DB efforts (Chicago, Ashburn) for peering with key partners to avoid Internet egress saturation

Associate Network Engineer II - Amway Global | Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

- Maintained global DMVPN connectivity across branches, standardized network provisioning templates and follow-the-sun support model.
- Campus datacenter and wireless network management and troubleshooting

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- AWS Certified Advanced Networking Specialty
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Solutions Architect Expert
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- Cisco CCNA (expired)

EDUCATION

- Davenport University BSc, Network Management and Security (Honors)
- Grand Rapids Community College AAAS, Computer Info Systems Network Admin (Honors)
- University of Pennsylvania, Wharton Certificate, Entrepreneurship
- Oregon State University Computer Science (incomplete)